Samantha Considine

(267) 769-8732 I samlconsidine@gmail.com I Bellmawr, NJ I slconsidine.github.io/Portfolio LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/samantha-considine I Github: github.com/slconsidine

Summary

Ambitious Full Stack Web Developer with background in information technology within higher education. Excels under pressure and has strong communication skills working as a collaborative team member. Passionate about continuing to learn and grow in all aspects of the field especially as it relates to improving the quality of user experience.

Technical Skills

Front End: React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, CSS, HTML

Back End: Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars.js, ORM, Firebase, AJAX

Projects

Geo Kathy I https://sheltered-cliffs-20791.herokuapp.com

Geo Kathy is a location based application that offers recommendations for what to do in an area based on local perspective. Users can create accounts and post their own reviews as well as upvote posts they found helpful.

Technology Used: React, Express, MongoDB, Node.js, Mongoose, JavaScript, Redux, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, APIs

Philadelphia Eagles Trivia Game | https://slconsidine.github.io/TriviaGame

Created a trivia game using JavaScript for the logic and jQuery to manipulate the HTML. Each question is timed and the user's answers are logged as either correct, incorrect, or unanswered.

Technology Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Google Fonts

Work Experience

Audiovisual Technician - Wharton Computing - Philadelphia, PA

May 2018 to present

- Perform daily functionality checks to ensure classroom systems are ready for classes and events of the day and resolve any technical issues
- Respond to emergency issues from faculty/staff and provide a fix to get class underway as soon as possible
- Provide training of in-room technology for Wharton events including the use of telepresence and videoconferencing and troubleshoot any problems that arise
- Assist with the installation and implementation of new classroom and conference room technology

Audio Visual Services - Information Technology - Ithaca, NY

November 2016 to May 2018

- Provided assistance with repair/maintenance of audiovisual equipment across a variety of classroom systems
- Documented the progress of response to client's request
- ❖ Worked within a community of numerous departments and harvested an atmosphere focusing on customer service and teamwork

Sound Engineer - Ithaca College Recording Services - Ithaca, NY

August 2014 to May 2018

- * Recorded various concerts and recitals put on by students, faculty, and guest artists in the School of Music
- * Edited the audio for CD production to be archived as well as distributed amongst faculty and students
- * Provided live sound support for concerts and recitals taking place in the Ithaca College School of Music

Education

Coding Bootcamp Certificate - University of Pennsylvania

May 2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js, and ReactJS.

Ithaca College - Ithaca, NY

May 2018

Bachelor's of Music in Sound Recording Technology, Minor in Finance